American Society of Landscape Architects Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
American Society of Landscape Architects Records 1899-1966 (bulk 1925-1955)
MSS29082
American Society of Landscape Architects
11,000 items 32 containers 9 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Correspondence, letterbooks, subject files, reports from chapters and committees, printed material, and other records of the organization.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Organizations
American Society of Landscape Architects.
Subjects
Landscape architects.; Landscape architecture.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records of the American Society of Landscape Architects were given to the Library of Congress by the organization in 1969.
Access and Restrictions
The records of the American Society of Landscape Architects are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Organizational History
The American Society of Landscape Architects, the national professional association representing landscape architects, was founded in 1899 to establish landscape architecture as a profession, develope educational opportunities in the field, and provide a voice of advocacy for the profession.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the American Society of Landscape Architects span the years 1899-1966, with the bulk of the material dating from 1925 to 1955. The collection includes general correspondence, subject files, letterheads of society members, reports from chapters and committees, books, and letterbooks of outgoing correspondence. The records are organized into the following series: General Correspondence, Subject File, Chapter and Committee Reports, Letterheads of Members, Books, and Letterbooks.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in six series:
General Correspondence, 1906-1933
Subject File, 1900-1966
Chapter and Committee Reports, 1927-1955
Letterheads of Members, 1899-1931
Books, 1899-1959
Letterbooks, 1900-1909
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm99029082
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1906-1933 (Box 1-2)
  Correspondence and miscellaneous items.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1906-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921-1933 (Box 2)
- Subject File, 1900-1966 (Box 3-20)
  Correspondence, reports of meetings, printed matter, and miscellaneous items relating primarily to the organization's chapters and committees.
  Arranged by key word as supplied by the organization.
  - Committee on Applied Arts, 1927-1935 (Box 3)
  - Committee on American Academy in Rome, 1914-1955 (Box 3)
  - Committee on American Landscape Architecture, 1933-1935 (Box 3)
  - American Planning and Civic Association, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Committee on American Society of Landscape Architects, AIP, 1938-1957 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Annual Meetings, 1956-1960, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Committee on Associate and Student Affiliation, 1957-1960 (Box 3)
  - Associations, landscape architectural (Box 3)
    - California Council of Landscape Architects, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
    - Miscellany (Box 3)
  - Brochures, 1958-1960 (Box 3)
  - California State Board, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Certificates, 1916-1956 (Box 3)
  - Chapters general, 1938-1958 (Box 3)
  - City and regional parks and playgrounds, 1957-1961 (Box 3)
  - Civil Service Committee (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Code of Ethics, 1926-1950 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Competitions, 1916-1960 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Competitions, historical, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Historical competitions, Franklin D. Roosevelt Memorial, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Constitution and Bylaws, 1957-1960 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Definitions, 1932-1956 (Box 5)
  - Special Committee to Obtain Designs and Estimates, 1915-1920 (Box 5)
  - Executive Director, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Education, 1909-1960, (1 folder) (Box 5, Box 6)
  - Honorary elections, historical (Box 7)
  - Examining Board, 1910-1925, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Fee schedule, historical, 1924 (Box 7)
  - Glossary of housing terms (Box 7)
  - Committee on Housing, 1950-1960 (Box 7)
  - ICED, historical file (Box 8)
  - Index to works of landscape architecture (Box 8)
  - Committee on Insurance, 1956-1960 (Box 8)
  - Committee on Landscape Industry Conference, historical, 1960 (Box 8)
  - New legislation, historical file, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Legislation, 1932-1938 (Box 8)
  - Membership and deaths, historical (Box 8)
  - Committee on Membership, 1929-1960 (Box 8)
  - Membership qualifications, 1948-1960 (Box 8)
  - Membership resignation, historical, 1907-1936 (Box 8)
  - Membership secretary, historical (Box 8)
  - Michigan State University, East Lansing, Mich., historical (Box 8)
  - Missouri Valley chapter, historical 1960 (Box 8)
  - Committee on National Arboretum, 1932 (Box 9)
  - Committee on National Cemeteries, 1944-1946 (Box 9)
  - National Conference of Instructors in Landscape Architecture, historical, 1959 (Box 9)
  - National defense (Box 9)
    - Camouflage, 1942 (Box 9)
    - Circulars of information, 1940-1942 (Box 9)
    - General, 1940-1942 (Box 9)
  - Committee on National Historic Monuments, 1934 (Box 9)
  - New York chapter, historical, undated (Box 9)
  - Committee on Nominations, 1956-1958 (Box 9)
  - North Central States chapter, historical, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - Northern California chapter, historical, 1955-1960 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Occupational Classification, 1946-1947 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Olmsted Memorial, 1923-1960 (Box 9)
  - Organization and Development, 1950-1960 (Box 9)
  - Pacific Northwest chapter, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - Panama-Pacific Exposition, 1913-1915 (Box 9)
  - Parks (Box 10)
    - Committee on Central Park, New York, N.Y., 1927 (Box 10)
    - Committee on City Parks, Playgrounds and Public Property, 1945-1956 (Box 10)
    - Committee on Metropolitan and County Parks, 1943-1950 (Box 10)
    - Committee on National State Parks and Forests, historical, 1916-1960 (Box 10)
    - State parks, 1924-1939 (Box 10)
    - Pennsylvania chapter, historical, 1958-1960 (Box 10)
    - Committee on Personnel, 1926-1954 (Box 10)
  - Photographs (Box 11)
    - Historical file on chapters, 1960 (Box 11)
    - Historical file on works of landscape architects, 1962 (Box 11)
    - Members, 1952-1962 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1916-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee on City, Regional and National Planning, 1917-1959 (Box 12)
  - Committee on National Planning, 1933-1947 (Box 12)
  - Committee on Town Planning and Industrial Housing, 1922-1923 (Box 12)
  - Committee on Post-War Planning, 1943-1948 (Box 12)
  - Committee on Plant Nomenclature, 1916-1960 (Box 12)
  - Policies (Box 12)
    - Committee on Policies, 1914-1951 (Box 12)
    - Potomac chapter, historical, 1957-1960 (Box 12)
    - Committee on Practice of Landscape Architecture by Governmental Agencies, 1931-1936 (Box 12)
    - Professional collaboration, historical, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Committee on Professional and Governmental Relations (Box 13)
      - Contracts, 1935-1938 (Box 13)
      - General, 1937-1947 (Box 13)
      - Housing Division, 1934-1935 (Box 13)
      - Lack of credit, 1934-1941 (Box 13)
      - National Park Service, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Committee on Professional Charges (Box 13)
      - 1948-1955 (Box 13)
      - 1928-1947 (Box 14)
    - Hubbard-Taylor professional practice, 1933-1944 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Professional Practice, 1947-1948 (Box 14)
    - Committee on Statement of Professional Practice, 1936-1942 (Box 14)
    - Professional practice and charges, John C. Olmsted, 1900-1915 (Box 14)
    - Professional responsibilities (Box 14)
      - General, 1957 (Box 14)
      - Highway work, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
      - Military installations, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
    - Professional registration, historical (Box 14)
      - 1954-1960 (Box 14)
      - 1919-1957 (Box 15)
    - Professional registration, 1929-1939 (Box 16)
    - Committee on Professional Service (Box 16)
      - General, 1946-1960 (Box 16)
      - Federal Highway Administration, 1955-1956 (Box 16)
    - Public relations, 1916-1960 (Box 17)
    - Publication board, 1949-1960 (Box 17)
    - Publicity releases, historical, 1966 (Box 17)
    - Public Housing Administration, historical, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Quarterly (Box 17)
    - Committee on Quarterly, Landscape Architecture, 1935-1937 (Box 17)
    - Guarantees and sustaining subscriptions, Los Angeles, Calif., 1938-1940 (Box 17)
    - Committee on Relations with Trades, 1907-1941 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Review Requirements for Membership, 1942-1943 (Box 18)
    - Roads and highways, 1931-1947 (Box 18)
    - Historical (Box 18)
      - Roads, better highways, information foundation, 1960 (Box 18)
      - Rocky Mountain chapter, 1960-1962 (Box 18)
      - Short Course, Los Angeles, Calif., 1959 (Box 18)
      - Southeastern chapter, 1929-1960 (Box 18)
      - Southern California chapter, 1953-1960 (Box 18)
      - Southwest chapter, 1957-1960 (Box 18)
    - Public roads, 1948-1955 (Box 18)
    - Membership rosters, 1914-1961 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Seal, Certificates, and Letterhead, 1916-1939 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Site Planning, 1944-1945 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Society Seal, 1916-1946 (Box 18)
    - Committee on Special Studies, Roundtable Conference, 1945-1946 (Box 18)
    - Standard contracts and specifications, 1928-1938 (Box 19)
    - Committee on Standard Symbols, Scales, and Terminology for Planning Use, 1933-1938 (Box 19)
    - Committee on Traveling Exhibition (Box 19)
      - General, 1951-1954 (Box 19)
      - Traveling lecture, 1931-1933 (Box 19)
    - Historical (Box 19)
      - University of Illinois, Urbana, Ill. 1954 (Box 19)
      - Upstate New York chapter, 1957-1960 (Box 19)
    - National War Manpower Commission roster, 1940-1945 (Box 19)
    - Committee on War Memorials, 1918-1946 (Box 19)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 19)
    - Washington Bicentennial Commission, Sol Bloom, 1931-1932 (Box 19)
    - Committee on National Capital (Box 19)
      - 1943-1959 (Box 19)
      - 1919-1935 (Box 20)
    - National Commission of Fine Arts Commemorative Magazine, 1910-1950 (Box 20)
    - Committee on the National Capital (Box 20)
      - Commission of Fine Arts, 1940-1950 (Box 20)
      - National Capital Park and Planning Committee, historical file, 1949-1957 (Box 20)
    - White House grounds, 1951-1960 (Box 20)
    - Committee on Williamsburg Restoration, 1928-1952 (Box 20)
  - Yearbook Committee (Box 20)
- Chapter and Committee Reports, 1927-1955 (Box 21)
  Printed copies of chapter and committee reports.
  - 1927-1955 (Box 21)
- Letterheads of Members, 1899-1931 (Box 22)
  Letterheads of members prior to 1932.
  - circa 1899-circa 1931 (Box 22)
- Books, 1899-1959 (Box 23-31)
  Published books and periodicals.
  - Transactions of the American Society of Landscape Architects, 1909-1921 (Box 23)
  - Thomas H. Mawson, "The Art and Craft of Garden Making," 1907 (Box 23)
  - American Landscape Architecture, incomplete collection, 1929-1932 (Box 24)
  - Thomas H. Mawson, The Life and Work of an English Landscape Architect, an Autobiography 1927 (Box 25)
  - Henry Vincent Hubbard and Theodora Kimball, Landscape Architecture, 1920 (Box 25)
  - Lewis A. Coffin, Jr., Henry M. Polhemus, and Addison F. Worthington, Small French Buildings, 1921 (Box 26)
  - Transactions of the American Society of Landscape Architects, 1922-1926 (Box 26)
  - Mildred Stapley Byne and Arthur Byne, Spanish Gardens and Patios, 1924 (Box 27)
  - Percy S. Cane, Geoffrey Holme and Shirley B. Wainwright, Modern Gardens, British and Foreign, 1926-1927 (Box 27)
  - Yearbooks for the Boston Society of Landscape Architects, 1929, (2 vols.) (Box 28)
  - Yearbooks and catalogs for the New York chapter, 1926-1933, (10 vols.) (Box 28)
  - Illustrations of Work of Members (Box 29)
    - 1931, (4 vols.) (Box 29)
    - 1932-1934, (4 vols.) (Box 30)
  - Architecture and Design, vols. 3 (no. 8) and 22, (3 vols.) (Box 31)
  - Roster pressbook, 1899-1959 (Box 31)
  - Florida Landscape Architecture (periodical), 1936, (2 vols.) (Box 31)
- Letterbooks, 1900-1909 (Box 32)
  Letterbooks with copies of outgoing correspondence.
  - 1900-1909, (3 vols.) (Box 32)